http://www.stihl.com/imprint-privacy-policy.aspx?tab=2

Imprint & Privacy Policy of the STIHL Website | STIHL | STIHL
Imprint & Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting the STIHL Website. All the legal details of our Website are shown below.
STIHL is the name for exemplary quality and personal service. So we look forward to your questions, hints and suggestions for improving our Website.
Your STIHL Online Team
Terms of Use
Terms of Use
This website is operated by ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG ('STIHL'). STIHL's contact details are provided below. In using this website you agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions. If you do not accept these terms and conditions you should not access the website further. STIHL may revise these Terms of Use from time to time and you should check the terms then in force on each visit to this website.
1. Material incorporated in this website, including all trade marks and logos, belongs to STIHL or its licensors. You may download a single copy of material incorporated in the website for your own use to decide whether or not to purchase a STIHL product or to further your use of a previously-purchased product. Use of such material other than as provided is prohibited.
2. The material provided on this website is provided 'as is' and on an 'as available basis'.
3. Nothing shall limit STIHL's liability for death or personal injury caused by its negligence, or that of its employees. Subject to the above, STIHL shall not be liable for any damages, including indirect or consequential losses, loss of profits or data, or business interruption, arising from your use or inability to use this website, or your use of the information on this website, whether arising in contract, tort (including negligence) or otherwise.
4. Without prejudice to paragraph 3 above, STIHL provides the 'Know How' section of this website as preliminary guidance only and professional advice should be sought from your local STIHL dealer in respect of the matters dealt with in that section.
5. Any link that may be provided to any third party website is provided for your convenience. STIHL does not endorse the contents of any third party website to which a link is provided, and is not responsible for such websites. You use any link provided from this website entirely at your own risk.
Privacy Policy
ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG, Badstraße 115, D – 71336 Waiblingen (hereinafter “STIHL” or “we”) is glad you are visiting our websites and are interested in our company and products. For us, data protection is not mere lip service and for that reason we take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We handle your data with the utmost care and confidentiality and use it only within the confines of the applicable data protection provisions and of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) in particular.
Responsibility for processing personal data
STIHL bears responsibility for lawfully processing your data.
Processing usage data
When you visit our websites we store the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you visit us, those of our websites that you visit, the date and duration of your visit and information on the device (brand, model, operating system) and web browser you have used. We also collect your IP address, the last four places of which are however anonymised.
We process this usage data to facilitate your access to our services in technical terms (e.g. to adjust our services to the terminal device you are using), and to recognize and stop any misuse. We also use usage data in anonymised form for statistical purposes and to improve our website. The legal foundation for processing personal usage data is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR.
Use of first party cookies
We use what are known as cookies on various pages to make visiting out websites attractive and to facilitate the use of certain functions. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your terminal device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted at the end of the browser session, i.e. once the browser is closed (termed session cookies). Other cookies remain on your terminal device, allowing us or our partners to recognize your browser on your next visit (termed long-term cookies). Cookies cannot be used to provide access to other files on your computer or to determine your email address.
On this website, the cookies listed in the cookie information are used.
Insofar as we use cookies which are necessary for the provision of our websites, the legal basis for the processing of personal data using these cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR.
Personal data is only processed using cookies for marketing purposes or to generate statistics if you have given us your consent to this. The legal basis for this is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR.
You can withdraw your consent at any time without stating reasons by clicking on this link and adjusting the functions permitted.
Cookies are stored on your terminal device and you have full control over their use. You may deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings of the web browser. Cookies that are already stored may be deleted at any time. This may also be done by automated means. Should cookies be deactivated for our websites, you may possibly not be able to use all of the functions on the websites to the full extent.
Web analysis using Google Analytics
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). The office responsible for users in the EU, the EEA and Switzerland is Google Ireland Limited, Google Building Gordon House, 4 Barrow St, Dublin, Ireland. Google Analytics uses cookies permitting the use of the website by you to be analyzed. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is as a rule transferred to a Google server in the USA where it is stored.
The website of STIHL uses Google Analytics with the additional component “anonymize IP”. This means that your IP address, collected by Google Analytics, will be shortened by Google within Member States of the European Union or in other signatory states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area before it is transmitted to the USA. Only in exceptional cases will your full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened once it has arrived there.
Google uses this information on behalf of STIHL to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to render further services connected with website and internet use vis-à-vis the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be combined with other Google data.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
More detailed information on the terms and conditions of use and data protection can be found at https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html or at https://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html.
Use of the remarketing or “Similar Target Groups” function of Google Inc.
STIHL uses the remarketing or “Similar Target Groups” function of Google LLC. This function enables STIHL to approach visitors to the website with advertising in a targeted manner by placing personalized, interest-based advertisements for users of the website when they visit other websites within the Google Display Network. Google uses cookies to analyze website use, which forms the basis for creating interest-based advertisements. To this end, Google stores a small file with a sequence of numbers in the browsers of the visitors to the website. The visits to the website and anonymized data on the use of the website are collected via this number. Personal data of visitors to the website are generally not stored. Should you then visit a different website within the Google Display Network, advertisements will appear which are highly likely to take account of product and information areas selected beforehand.
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using cookies is Article 6 (1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
Further information on Google remarketing and Google’s privacy policy can be viewed at: https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/.
DoubleClick by Google
DoubleClick by Google is a service provided by Google LLC. DoubleClick by Google uses cookies to provide you with advertisements relevant to you. Your browser is assigned a pseudonym identification number (ID) in order to check which advertisements were displayed on your browser and which advertisements were selected. The cookies generally contain no personal information. The use of DoubleClick cookies merely enables Google and its partner websites to place advertisements based on previous visits to our or other websites on the internet. The information generated by the cookie is transmitted for evaluation purposes to a server in the USA where it is stored. Google only transmits data to third parties on the basis of statutory regulations or in the context of commissioned data processing. Under no circumstances will Google combine your data with other data collected by Google.
The legal foundation for processing personal data while using cookies is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also prevent Google from collecting and processing the data generated by the cookies and relating to your use of the websites by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en, under Ads Settings, extension for DoubleClick deactivation.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
Further information on terms of use and data protection can be found at https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html, or at https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/.
Tag Manager von Google
Google Tag Manager is a service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”) to enable tags to be created, updated and managed. Tags are small code elements on our website which, among other things, serve to measure traffic and visitor behaviour and to determine the impact of online advertising and social channels. Whenever you visit our website, the current tag configuration is sent to your browser. In that way you receive instructions as to which tags are to be triggered. The tool itself does not collect any personal data but it ensures that other tags are triggered which, in turn, may possibly collect data. You will find further information on the functioning of Google Tag Manager Tags at: https://support.google.com/tagmanager/answer/2772432?hl=de&topic=2574304&ctx=topic and in the use policy: https://www.google.de/tagmanager/use-policy.html.
Google Web Fonts
Google Web Fonts are used to improve the optical appearance of different pieces of information on this website (https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Roboto and https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Roboto+Condensed). The Web Fonts are transferred to the cache of your browser to allow them to be used for the presentation. Should the browser not support Google Web Fonts or prevent access to the same, the text will be shown in standard print.
Google Webfonts “Roboto” and “Roboto Condensed” are licensed under Apache License 2.0:
http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0. Information on privacy is retrievable at the Google Privacy Center at: http://www.google.com/intl/de-DE/policies/privacy/.
Use of Google Ads Conversion Tracking
We use as a Google Ads customer Google Conversion Tracking, an analysis service provided by Google LLC. A cookie (“conversion cookie”) is placed on your computer by Google Ads if you have been directed to our website via a Google Ad. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used to identify individuals. If you visit certain pages of this website and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google can recognize that someone has clicked on the ad and been directed to our website. Every Google Ads customer receives another cookie. Cookies cannot be tracked therefore across the websites of Ads customers. The information obtained with the help of the conversion cookies is used to generate anonymous conversion statistics for Ads customers who have decided to use conversion tracking. The Ads customers learn the total number of users who have clicked on their advertisement and were directed to a page with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information with which users can be personally identified.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
Further information on terms of use and data protection can be found at https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/ or at https://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html.
Microsoft Bing
This website uses Bing Ads, a program provided by Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA, through which data is collected and stored. With this data, usage profiles are generated using pseudonyms. This service allows us to monitor the activities of users on our website if they are directed to our website via advertisements of Bing Ads. If you are directed to our website via such an advertisement, a cookie is placed on your computer. A Bing UET tag is integrated on our website. This is a code which, in combination with the cookie, stores some non-personal data about the usage of the website (the time spent on the website, areas of the website accessed). No information about your identity is collected. Bing Ads is used to ensure that the design of the website meets the needs of customers and to improve the website. Microsoft has signed up to the Privacy Shield.
The information collected is transferred Microsoft servers in the USA, where it is stored for no more than 180 days. If you do not want your information to be collected, you can deactivate the placement of cookies via your internet browser's settings. By using the consumer opt-out website provided by the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/, you can check which of the participating websites place cookies in your browser and deactivate these. Microsoft can also monitor your usage behavior across several of your electronic devices with cross-device tracking and as a result is able to display personalized advertising on or in Microsoft websites and apps. You can deactivate this behavior under https://choice.microsoft.com/de-de/opt-out.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
Further information on the analysis services provided by Bing can be found at the Bing Ads website: https://help.ads.microsoft.com/#apex/3/en/53056/2. Further information on data protection at Microsoft and Bing can be found in Microsoft’s privacy statement: https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement.
Facebook conversion tracking
This website uses for marketing purposes the conversion tracking of “Facebook Pixel”, a service provided by Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA (“Facebook”). The office responsible for users in the EU, the EEA and Switzerland is Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canals Square, Dublin, Ireland. We use this service to analyze and statistically evaluate the general use of our website and in doing so track and assess the effectiveness of Facebook advertising (“conversion tracking”). To this end, Facebook processes data collected on our websites through cookies and similar technologies.
The data collected in this connection is anonymous to us and does not allow us to draw any conclusions about the identity of users. However, this data is transferred for analysis purposes by Facebook to a server in the USA, where it is stored For cases where personal data is transferred to the USA, Facebook has signed up to the EU-US Privacy Shield. Further information on this can be found at https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome.
If you are a member of Facebook and have allowed Facebook to do this via your account’s privacy settings, Facebook can also link the information collected by us about your visit to your member account and use this for the targeted placement of Facebook ads. You can view and change the privacy settings of your Facebook profile at any time at https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR.  You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also delete cookies which have already been stored in your browser’s settings. If you do this, it may be the case that you no longer have full use of all of the functions of the websites.
Outbrain
On our website we use technologies (widgets) provided by Outbrain Inc. ("Outbrain"), 39 W 13th Street New York, NY 10011 USA.
We do not collect or process any personal data of users in connection with the use of Outbrain widgets. With Outbrain we record the visibility of our content and assess the attention focus. This is used to ensure the optimal arrangement and placement of our editorial content in order to track and assess its effectiveness.
The content displayed in the widget is controlled content and technology wise by Outbrain, with our users being made aware of further content of third-party websites which may be of interest to them. In order to display this further content which may be of interest, Outbrain uses cookies. Further information on the cookies used by Outbrain can be found at https://www.outbrain.com/legal/#cookies.
As the controller, Outbrain provides information on the collection and use of usage and other data in Outbrain’s privacy policy, which can be viewed at https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy. Insofar as personal data is transferred from the European Economic Area by Outbrain to other countries whose applicable laws do not provide the same level of data protection as in the European Economic Area, Outbrain ensures a suitable level of protection is provided with measures required by law.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
You can also opt out of the use of usage and other data by Outbrain at any time at https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy#privacy-policy. After declaring your opt-out, Outbrain's content/recommendations will no longer be controlled based on content searched by you.
Indeed Conversion Pixel
This website uses the conversion tracking function of Indeed Ireland Operations Limited, 124 St. Stephen’s Green, Dublin 2, Ireland. If you click on a job advertisement placed by us on Indeed, a cookie (conversion cookie) will be placed on your computer. These cookies lose their validity in 30 days and do not serve for personal identification purposes but for identifying how many of the applications we received came from our job advertisement on Indeed. The information obtained with the aid of the conversion cookie serves for drawing up our conversion statistics. We learn of the total number of users who clicked on our advertisement and sent an application. Generally, no information is revealed however by which users can be identified in person. Further information on the data protection provisions of Indeed is available via the following internet address: https://de.indeed.com/legal.
Should you prefer not to participate in conversion tracking, you may object to this use by deactivating the cookie via your web browser. You will then not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using conversion tracking is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR.
Criteo
This website uses a technology provided by Criteo GmbH, Unterer Anger 3, 80331 Munich (“Criteo”). Through this, information on the surfing behavior of website visitors is collected for marketing purposes in purely anonymized form and cookies are placed for this purpose. Criteo can therefore analyze the surfing behavior and then display targeted recommendations as suitable advertising banners when other websites are visited. Under no circumstances can the data collected be used to personally identify the visitor to the website. The data collected by Criteo is only used to improve the advertising. The data is not used for other purposes or disclosed to third parties. Further information on data protection at Criteo can be found at https://www.criteo.com/de/privacy/.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is provided by Art. 6 (1)(1)(a) GDPR. You can withdraw this consent at any time as described above by adjusting your cookie preferences.
In addition, a small "i" (for Information) appears in the bottom right corner of every banner displayed, which opens if you place the mouse over it and, if you click on it, directs you to a new page on which the system is explained and an opt-out is offered. If you click on Opt out, an "opt-out” cookie is placed which prevents this banner from being displayed in future.
Social media and social plugins
We also offer you comprehensive personal support via our pages in the social media. Should you have a query about any of the social media, we will forward it to the responsible department. The data are used exclusively for purposes of replying to your query and are not passed on to third parties. The legal foundation for processing personal data in the context of dealing with your query is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR. In order to contact us via the social media, you need to register with these services. The companies behind such services may possibly process personal data. We have no influence over the nature, extent and processing of these data.
Recommendation via social networks using Shariff
We use the Heise solution termed “Shariff” to integrate the social plugins of Facebook, Twitter, Google+ and Instagram that function as a recommendation (“Share”, “Like”, “+1”, “Camera”/”Share”, “Camera Symbol”).
Shariff prevents your IP address from being transmitted to the provider of the particular social network. Instead of your server address it is only the server address that is transmitted. Your IP address is therefore not passed on.
Use of Facebook plugins
Our website makes use of the social plugin (“plugins”) of social network Facebook operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). You will find an overview of Facebook plugins and their appearance at: https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins.
If you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser will make a direct connection to the servers of Facebook. The content of the plugin is conveyed directly to your browser by Facebook and integrated into the page. Such integration allows Facebook to receive the information that your browser has accessed the relevant page of our website even if you have no profile on Facebook or are not logged on to Facebook at that particular moment. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted from your browser directly to a server of Facebook in the USA where it is stored. If you are logged on to Facebook, Facebook will be able to directly associate the visit to our website with your Facebook profile. If you interact with the plugins, by making a comment for example, this information will likewise be transmitted directly to a Facebook server where it is stored. The information will also be published on your Facebook profile and shown to your Facebook friends. We wish to point out that in our capacity as the website provider we are not informed of the content of the data transmitted or of their use by Facebook. Please consult Facebook’s notes on data protection for the purpose and extent of the collection of data by Facebook along with your rights in that regard and possible settings to protect your privacy at: https://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php.
Should you not wish Facebook to directly associate your Facebook profile with the data collected via our website, you need to log off from Facebook prior to visiting our website. You are also able prevent Facebook plugins from being loaded at all by using add-ons for your browser, e.g. by way of a “Facebook blocker”.
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using the plugin is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (f) GDPR.
Use of YouTube plugins
The social plugins (“plugins”) of social network YouTube, a service provided by Google LLC, are used on our website.
If you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser will make a direct connection to the servers of Google. The content of the plugin is conveyed directly to your browser by Google and integrated into the page. Such integration allows Google to receive the information that your browser has accessed the relevant page of our website even if you do not possess a YouTube account or are not logged on to YouTube at that particular moment. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted from your browser directly to a server of Google in the USA where it is stored.
If you are registered with YouTube, Google will be able to directly associate the visit to our website with your respective account. We wish to point out that in our capacity as the website provider we are not informed of the content of the data transmitted or of their use by Google. Please consult Google’s notes on data protection for the purpose and extent of the collection of data by Google along with your rights in that regard and possible settings to protect your privacy at: https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/.
Should you not wish Google to directly associate your account with YouTube with the data collected via our website, you need to log off from YouTube prior to visiting our website. You are also able prevent Google plugins from being loaded at all by using add-ons for your browser, e.g. by way of script blocker “NoScript”: https://noscript.net/.
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using the plugin is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (b) or (f) GDPR.
Use of Twitter plugins
Our website makes use of the social plugins (“plugins”) of microblogging service Twitter operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”). You will find an overview of Twitter plugins and their appearance at: https://about.twitter.com/en_us/company/brand-resources.html.
If you access a page of our website that contains such a plugin, your browser will make a direct connection to the servers of Twitter. The content of the plugin is conveyed directly to your browser by Twitter and integrated into the page. Such integration allows Twitter to receive the information that your browser has accessed the relevant page of our website even if you have no profile on Twitter or are not logged on to Twitter at that particular moment. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted from your browser directly to a server of Twitter in the USA where it is stored.
If you are logged on to Twitter, Twitter will be able to directly associate the visit to our website with your Twitter account. The information will also be published on your Twitter account and shown to your contacts. We wish to point out that in our capacity as the website provider we are not informed of the content of the data transmitted or of their use by Twitter. Please consult Twitter’s notes on data protection for the purpose and extent of the collection of data by Twitter along with your rights in that regard and possible settings to protect your privacy at: https://twitter.com/privacy.
Should you not wish Twitter to directly associate your Twitter account with the data collected via our website, you need to log off from Twitter prior to visiting our website. You are also able prevent Twitter plugins from being loaded at all by using add-ons for your browser, e.g. by way of script blocker “NoScript”: http://noscript.net/.
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using the plugin is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (b) or (f) GDPR.
Use of Instagram plugins
Our website uses so-called social plug-ins (‘plug-ins’) from Instagram, which is operated by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA (“Instagram”). The plug-ins are indicated by an Instagram logo, such as in the form of an ‘Instagram camera’. An overview of the Instagram plug-ins and what they look like can be found here: http://blog.instagram.com/post/36222022872/introducing-instagram-badges
When you access a page of our website that contains such a plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection to Instagram’s servers. The content of the plug-in is sent directly from Instagram to your browser and is integrated into the page. By integrating the plug-ins, Instagram is notified that your browser has accessed the corresponding page of our website, even if you do not have an Instagram profile or are not logged in to Instagram at the time. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted by your browser directly to an Instagram server in the USA, where it is stored.
If you are logged in to Instagram, Instagram can directly associate the visit to our website with your Instagram account. If you interact with the plug-ins, for example by clicking the “Instagram” button, this information is likewise transmitted directly to an Instagram server, where it is stored. The information is also published on your Instagram account and made visible to your contacts there.
The purpose and scope of the collection and further processing and use of data by Instagram as well as your rights in this regard and setting options for protecting your privacy can be found in Instagram’s privacy policy: https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388/
If you do not wish for Instagram to directly associate the data collected via our website with your Instagram account, you must log out of Instagram before visiting our website. You can also completely prevent the Instagram plug-ins from loading by using browser add-ons, e.g. the ‘NoScript’ script blocker (http://noscript.net/).
The legal foundation for processing personal data by using the plugin is Article 6(1) first subparagraph (b) or (f) GDPR.
Newsletter, ordering of printed matter and contact
If you would like to receive the newsletter offered on the website, we need from you an e-mail address, title and your surname. Further information can be provided voluntarily. When you register, the date and time of the registration, the confirmation of the data protection regulations, the type of newsletter and the e-mail verification are stored. This data is stored exclusively for the purpose of sending you the newsletter and tracking any possible misuse of an e-mail address. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs at the basic rates. For this purpose, you only need to contact us via the form https://www.stihl.de/newsletter-abbestellen.aspx.
The legal basis for the processing of the aforementioned data is provided by Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR.
If you contact us by telephone, e-mail, post, contact form or in any other way with an inquiry or if we contact you, we also process your personal data, e.g. name, address, telephone number and the content of the message. This information is processed exclusively for the purpose of ensuring your inquiry is dealt with correctly. Your data is used only to the extent necessary for this purpose. If necessary, e.g. because your inquiry concerns the ordering of printed matter which is held by another company of the STIHL Group or as part of the Customer Support Service, your data will be disclosed to this other company of the STIHL Group if and to the extent which this is necessary to deal with your inquiry. The legal basis for the processing of the aforementioned data is provided by Art. 6 (1)(1)(b)GDPR, if this is in connection with the initiation or performance of a contract, e.g. in the case of complaints, or by Art. 6 (1)(1) GDPR, because we have a legitimate interest in exchanging business correspondence with you. Communication data is deleted if it is no longer needed for communication with you and any statutory retention requirements have expired.
Telephone conversations with our Customer Support are only recorded with your prior consent for quality assurance or training purposes and deleted after no more than 90 days. The consent to the recording of the conversation is of course given on a voluntary basis. You can withdraw the consent at any time with effect for the future, for example by asking the employee on the telephone to stop recording the conversation. Your data is processed on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 (1) first subparagraph (a) GDPR).
For our Customer Support Services, we use service providers with which corresponding contract data processing agreements have been concluded pursuant to Art. 28 GDPR.
Duration of the processing of usage data
Usage of personal data processed during the visit of our website are stored for a period of 7 days. The data of the data subject specified in this section will otherwise be deleted where knowledge thereof is no longer required for the purposes described, unless statutory provisions stipulate longer storage.
Your rights
You have a right to be informed of personal data processed by STIHL and, where the relevant statutory requirements are met, a right to rectification, erasure and restriction of processing. You also have the right to receive the personal data provided by you in a structured, common and machine-readable format. This includes the right to transfer such data to a different data controller. So far as such is technically possible, you may also request that STIHL transfers the personal data directly to the other data controller.
To exercise the aforementioned rights and in the event of queries and complaints relating to the use of your personal data you may approach the data protection officer of STIHL:
Contact Data Protection Officer
ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG
Data protection officer
Stuttgarter Straße 80
D – 71332 Waiblingen
E-Mail: datenschutz@stihl.de
You also have the right to approach the responsible data protection commissioner with a complaint.
Data Privacy Statement as at: February 2020
Supplier
ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG
Badstraße 115
D-71336 Waiblingen
Tel.: +49 7151 26-0
E-mail: info@stihl.de
Limited partnership with registered office in Waiblingen, HRA 260269, District Court Stuttgart
General partners: Hans Peter Stihl and STIHL Aktiengesellschaft with registered office in Waiblingen, HRB 263722, District Court Stuttgart
The Approved representative is the Executive Board of STIHL AG:
Dr. Bertram Kandziora, Chairman of the Executive Board
Karl Angler, Head of Finance and Information Technology
Anke Kleinschmit, Head of Development
Norbert Pick, Head of Marketing and Sales
Dr. Michael Prochaska, Head of Human Resources and Legal Affairs
Martin Schwarz, Head of Manufacturing and Materials
Chairman of the Supervisory Board of STIHL Aktiengesellschaft: Dr. Nikolas Stihl
VAT identification number: DE 147330096
Note:
The EU Commission offers the possibility of online dispute resolution on an online platform operated by it. This platform can be reached via the external link http://ec.europa.eu/consumers/odr/ . We are not obliged to participate in arbitration proceedings and unfortunately cannot offer participation in such proceedings."
Legal Notice
By visiting or using the STIHL Website you agree to the following conditions of use.
Copyright
All text, pictures, graphics, audio files and other information published here and their design (content) are protected by copyright. Unless otherwise stated only ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG is Approved to use this protected content.
Reproduction and/or transmission of the whole or parts of the site is permissible only with the written consent of ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG. In particular, it is not permissible to copy pictures or designs from the Website and use them for your own purposes.
Trademarks
The STIHL name ,
the STIHL spare parts logo
and the color combination orange/light grey
are registered trademarks of ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG. In addition, ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG owns numerous other protected trademarks. The use of trademarks demands written consent of the trademark owner.
Disclaimer
Our Website content is subject to constant change. While ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG takes the greatest possible care in compiling its Web pages, we nevertheless cannot guarantee that the content is complete or correct. ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG will not be held liable for direct or consequential damage (contractual and non-contractual liability) due to use of the information and data on this Website unless in case of intent or gross negligence on the part of ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG.
ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG will not be held liable for and does not warrant the content of Websites to which our Website provides a direct or indirect link. Visitors follow links to other Websites and home pages at their own risk and use them in accordance with the conditions of use applicable to the Websites concerned.
Cookie Information
Name of the cookie: _ga
Storage duration: 2 years
Purpose: Is used for the differentiation of users.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _gid
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Is used for the differentiation of users.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _gat
Storage duration: 1 minute
Purpose: Is used to throttle the request rate. If Google Analytics is provided via Google Tag Manager, this cookie is called _dc_gtm_<property-id>.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: AMP_TOKEN
Storage duration: 30 seconds to 1 year
Purpose: Contains a token with which a Client ID can be retrieved from the AMP Client ID Service. Other possible values indicate a logoff, an inflight query or an error when retrieving a client ID from the AMP Client ID Service.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _gac_<property-id>
Storage duration: 90 days
Purpose: Contains campaign-dependent information for the user. When your Google Analytics- and Google Ads accounts are linked, the Google-Ads-website-conversion-tags will read this cookie, except you decided against it. Find out more.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utma
Storage duration: 2 years after set up / update
Purpose: Is used to differentiate users and sessions. The cookie is created, when the Javascript-library runs and no __utma-cookies are existent. The cookie gets updated, each time when the data is sent to Google Analytics.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utmt
Storage duration: 10 minutes
Purpose: Is used to throttle the request rate.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utmb
Storage duration: 30 minutes after set up / update
Purpose: Is used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created, when the Javascript-library runs and no __utmb-cookies are existent. The cookie gets updated, each time when the data is sent to Google Analytics.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utmc
Storage duration: End of browser session
Purpose: Is not used in ga.js. Set for interoperability with urchin.js. In the past this cookie was used in combination with __utmb-Cookie, to determine, whether the user was in a new session/visit.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utmz
Storage duration: 6 months after set up / update
Purpose: Saves the traffic-source or -campaign how the user reached the website. The cookie is created, when the Javascript-library runs, and gets updated with each data transmission to Google Analytics.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: __utmv
Storage duration: 2 years after set up / update
Purpose: Used to store user-defined variable data at visitor level. This cookie is created when a developer uses the _setCustomVar method with a user-defined variable at the visitor level. This cookie was also used for the deprecated _setVar method. The cookie is updated each time data is sent to Google Analytics.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _gaexp
Storage duration: Depends on the duration of the experiment but usually 90 days.
Purpose: Is used to determine the inclusion of a user in an experiment and the procedure of experiments in which a user has been included.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _opt_awcid
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Is used for campaigns, which are assigned to the customer-IDs of Google Ads.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _opt_awmid
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Is used for campaigns, which are assigned to the customer-IDs of Google Ads.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _opt_awgid
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Is used for campaigns, which are displayed on Google Ads Ad Group Ids.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _opt_awkid
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Is used for campaigns, which are displayed on Google Ads Criterion Ids.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: _opt_utmc
Storage duration: 24 hours
Purpose: Stores the last utm_campaign query parameter
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: gtm_internal
Storage duration: 30 days
Purpose: Is used to recognise the internal traffic of STIHL and its partners. For external users the value will be statically "false".
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: swd
Storage duration: 30 minutes
Purpose: Is used to indicate that the weather data of the user's location has already been sent to Google Analytics within the last 30 minutes.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: IDE
Storage duration: 1 year
Purpose: Is used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user's actions after seeing or clicking on one of the advertiser's ads, with the goal of measuring the effectiveness of an ad and presenting targeted ads to the user.
Provider: Google
Category: Statistics
Name of the cookie: ASP.NET_SessionId
Storage duration: Session (=until browser is closed)
Purpose: ASP.NET_Session Cookie
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: .ASPXAUTH
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Login Cookie media area
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: locatorAttr[...]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Retailer search attribute options
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: stihl_slider-light
Storage duration: 10 days
Purpose: Wood/plant advisor/options
Provider: STIHL
Storage duration: 30 years
Purpose: Cookie to save the kind of tree the user chose in the tree lexicon.
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: kiosk
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Retailer search kiosk mode for a fair
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: NoMobile
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: User wants to visit the desktop version with a mobile terminal.
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: allowCookies
Storage duration: 3600 days
Purpose: Allows user cookies
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: stihl_cookie_info_seen
Storage duration: 9999 days
Purpose: The value is accumulated per page visit. After 3 page visits the newsletter layer is displayed.
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: stihl-action-for-newsletter
Storage duration: Accept: 1000 days; Closed: 30 days
Purpose: Is set, when a button in the newsletter layer is clicked.
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: noDesktop
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Desktop/Mobile Switch
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: langSelected
Storage duration: 3650 days
Purpose: Choosen language (multilingual websites)
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: productCatalogNotepad
Storage duration: 30 days
Purpose: Saves article Ids which have been put on the wishlist
Provider: STIHL
Category: Necessary
Name of the cookie: fr
Storage duration: 3 months
Purpose: Is used by Facebook to deliver a range of advertising products such as real-time third-party bidding.
Provider: Facebook
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: tr
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Is used by Facebook to deliver a range of advertising products such as real-time third-party bidding.
Provider: Facebook
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: GPS
Storage duration: 1 day
Purpose: Registers a unique ID on mobile terminal, to enable the registration based on the geographic position.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: PREF
Storage duration: 8 months
Purpose: Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics about how visitors use YouTube videos on different websites.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
Storage duration: 179 days
Purpose: Tries to estimate the bandwidth of users on sites with integrated YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: YSC
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Registers a unique ID to keep statistics on what videos from YouTube the user has seen.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-cast-installed [x2]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-connected-devices [x2]
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-device-id [x2]
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-fast-check-period [x2]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-session-app [x2]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: yt-remote-session-name [x2]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Saves the videoplayer settings of a user for embedded YouTube videos.
Provider: YouTube
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: _hjid
Storage duration: 1 year
Purpose: Sets a unique ID for a session. With this the website gets data on visitor behaviour for statistical purpose.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: _hjIncludedInSample
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Determines whether the user's navigation should be registered in a specific statistical placeholder.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ajs_anonymous_id
Storage duration: 1 year
Purpose: This cookie is used to identify a specific user - this information is used to identify the number of specific users on the website.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ajs_group_properties
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Collects data from visitors. This information is used to categorize visitors into segments, which allows more efficient advertising.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ajs_user_traits
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Collects data from visitors. This information is used to categorize visitors into segments, which allows more efficient advertising.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: amplitude_unsent_#GUID#
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Is used in combination with the pop-up questionnaires and user ID of the website - The data obtained from this is used for statistical marketing purposes.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: amplitude_unsent_identify_#GUID#
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Is used in combination with the pop-up questionnaires and user ID of the website - The data obtained from this is used for statistical marketing purposes.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ki_r
Storage duration: 5 years
Purpose: Is used to capture, which questions the user has seen. With this it is guaranteed that the same questions are not displayed again.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ki_t
Storage duration: 5 years
Purpose: Is used to capture, which questions the user has seen. With this it is guaranteed that the same questions are not displayed again.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: _hjTLDTest
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: More information to follow
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: amplitude_id_b37a423901694056906133c8c13c895dcriteo.com
Storage duration: 10 years
Purpose: More information to follow
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: pa-l
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Necessary for the integration of Pinterest on the website. Pinterest.com offers an audiovisual service on the website.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: pa-l_enabled
Storage duration: Persistent
Purpose: Necessary for the integration of Pinterest on the website. Pinterest.com offers an audiovisual service on the website.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: pardot [x2]
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Is used to identify the visitor across visits and devices. This enables the website to present relevant advertising to the visitor. The service is provided by third-party advertising spots that enable real-time bidding for advertisers.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: zdi
Storage duration: 1 day
Purpose: Collects anonymous information about the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the site and which pages were loaded, for the purpose of displaying targeted ads.
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: cookieMsg
Storage duration: 1 year
Purpose: More information to follow
Provider: Criteo
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: multivariate_test_variation_id21
Storage duration: 3 months
Purpose: Contains the anonymous User-ID. Used for tracking user actions, such as clicks on the recommendations.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: auid
Storage duration: 90 days
Purpose: Contains the Advertising ID of the user on mobile devices. Used for tracking user actions, such as clicks on the recommendations.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: _ofcap_DOC1
Storage duration: 7 days
Purpose: Is used for the limitation of the frequency.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: recs-{}
Storage duration: 1 minute or refresh
Purpose: Saves the documents we recommend so that we do not show you the same recommendation.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: ref-{}
Storage duration: 1 minute
Purpose: Saves referring document information - written by forwarding on click.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: spuid
Storage duration: 12 months
Purpose: Saves the registered uuid - only for registered users.
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: spv
Storage duration: 12 months
Purpose: Signals, that this user already visited the sphere (and is considered as sphere user) - for anonymous users
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: sprm
Storage duration: 12 months
Purpose: Sphere's "remember-me" cookie - only for registered users
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: SPHERE_JSESSIONID
Storage duration: Session
Purpose: Session identification
Provider: Outbrain
Category: Marketing
Name of the cookie: adconv
Storage duration: 30 days
Purpose: When a job seeker goes to the advertiser's thank you page, the request is sent to "conv.indeed.com/pagead/conv/{Inserenten-Nummer}" by beacon script found by each advertiser. Conversion tracker record the conversion by creating an "adConversion" logbook based on the "adconv" cookie.
Provider: Indeed
Category: Marketing
Startup page
Site map
Imprint & Legal Notice
Privacy Policy
Print
Recommend
Become a fan of:
YoutubeChannel
ANDREAS STIHL AG & Co. KG, D-71336 Waiblingen
